{"test_questions": [[{"question": "On the fifth clock pulse, a 4-bit Johnson sequence is Q0 = 0, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, and Q3 = 1. On the sixth clock pulse, the sequence is ________.", "opta": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "optb": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, Q3 = 0", "optc": "Q0 = 0, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 1, Q3 = 1", "optd": "Q0 = 0, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bit sequence 0010 is serially entered (right-most bit first) into a 4-bit parallel out shift register that is initially clear. What are the Q outputs after two clock pulses?", "opta": "0000", "optb": "0010", "optc": "1000", "optd": "1111", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a shift register that will accept a parallel input, or a bidirectional serial load and internal shift features, called?", "opta": "tristate", "optb": "end around", "optc": "universal", "optd": "conversion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On the third clock pulse, a 4-bit Johnson sequence is Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, and Q3 = 0. On the fourth clock pulse, the sequence is ________.", "opta": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 1, Q3 = 1", "optb": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 1, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "optc": "Q0 = 1, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "optd": "Q0 = 0, Q1 = 0, Q2 = 0, Q3 = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A bidirectional 4-bit shift register is storing the nibble 1101. Its  input is HIGH. The nibble 1011 is waiting to be entered on the serial data-input line. After three clock pulses, the shift register is storing ________.", "opta": "1101", "optb": "0111", "optc": "0001", "optd": "1110", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How can parallel data be taken out of a shift register simultaneously?", "opta": "Use the Q output of the first FF.", "optb": "Use the Q output of the last FF.", "optc": "Tie all of the Q outputs together.", "optd": "Use the Q output of each FF.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is meant by parallel load of a shift register?", "opta": "All FFs are preset with data.", "optb": "Each FF is loaded with data, one at a time.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the output enable do on the 74395A chip?", "opta": "It determines when data can be loaded.", "optb": "It forces all outputs to go HIGH.", "optc": "It forces all outputs to go LOW.", "optd": "It activates the three-state buffer.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To operate correctly, starting a ring shift counter requires:", "opta": "clearing all the flip-flops", "optb": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all others", "optc": "clearing one flip-flop and presetting all others", "optd": "presetting all the flip-flops", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a 6-bit Johnson counter sequence there are a total of how many states, or bit patterns?", "opta": "2", "optb": "6", "optc": "12", "optd": "24", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A modulus-12 ring counter requires a minimum of ________.", "opta": "10 flip-flops", "optb": "12 flip-flops", "optc": "6 flip-flops", "optd": "2 flip-flops", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stepper motors have become popular in digital automation systems because ________.", "opta": "of their low cost", "optb": "they are driven by sequential digital signals", "optc": "they can be used to provide repetitive mechanical movement", "optd": "they are driven by sequential digital signals and can be used to provide repetitive mechanical movement", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The group of bits 11001 is serially shifted (right-most bit first) into a 5-bit parallel output shift register with an initial state 01110. After three clock pulses, the register contains ________.", "opta": "01110", "optb": "00001", "optc": "00101", "optd": "00110", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assume that a 4-bit serial in/serial out shift register is initially clear. We wish to store the nibble 1100. What will be the 4-bit pattern after the second clock pulse? (Right-most bit first.)", "opta": "1100", "optb": "0011", "optc": "0000", "optd": "1111", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A serial in/parallel out, 4-bit shift register initially contains all 1s. The data nibble 0111 is waiting to enter. After four clock pulses, the register contains ________.", "opta": "0000", "optb": "1111", "optc": "0111", "optd": "1000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 200 kHz clock frequency, eight bits can be serially entered into a shift register in ________.", "opta": "4 \u03bcs", "optb": "40 \u03bcs", "optc": "400 \u03bcs", "optd": "40 ms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An 8-bit serial in/serial out shift register is used with a clock frequency of 2 MHz to achieve a time delay (td) of ________.", "opta": "16 s", "optb": "8 s", "optc": "4 s", "optd": "2 s", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sequence of equally spaced timing pulses may be easily generated by which type of counter circuit?", "opta": "ring shift", "optb": "clock", "optc": "Johnson", "optd": "binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bit sequence 10011100 is serially entered (right-most bit first) into an 8-bit parallel out shift register that is initially clear. What are the Q outputs after four clock pulses?", "opta": "10011100", "optb": "11000000", "optc": "00001100", "optd": "11110000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If an 8-bit ring counter has an initial state 10111110, what is the state after the fourth clock pulse?", "opta": "11101011", "optb": "00010111", "optc": "11110000", "optd": "00000000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How would a latch circuit be used in a microprocessor system?", "opta": "as transportation for Intel employees", "optb": "for a group of data that is the same", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 4-bit shift register that receives 4 bits of parallel data will shift to the ________ by ________ position(s) for each clock pulse.", "opta": "right, one", "optb": "right, two", "optc": "left, one", "optd": "left, three", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many clock pulses will be required to completely load serially a 5-bit shift register?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is a strobe signal used when serially loading a shift register?", "opta": "to turn the register on and off", "optb": "to control the number of clocks", "optc": "to determine which output Qs are used", "optd": "to determine the FFs that will be used", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An 8-bit serial in/serial out shift register is used with a clock frequency of 150 kHz. What is the time delay between the serial input and the Q3 output?", "opta": "1.67 s", "optb": "26.67 s", "optc": "26.7 ms", "optd": "267 ms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the three output conditions of a three-state buffer?", "opta": "HIGH, LOW, float", "optb": "1, 0, float", "optc": "both of the above", "optd": "neither of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary purpose of a three-state buffer is usually:", "opta": "to provide isolation between the input device and the data bus", "optb": "to provide the sink or source current required by any device connected to its output without loading down the output device", "optc": "temporary data storage", "optd": "to control data flow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a ring shift counter and a Johnson shift counter?", "opta": "There is no difference.", "optb": "A ring is faster.", "optc": "The feedback is reversed.", "optd": "The Johnson is faster.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a recirculating register?", "opta": "serial out connected to serial in", "optb": "all Q outputs connected together", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When is it important to use a three-state buffer?", "opta": "when two or more outputs are connected to the same input", "optb": "when all outputs are normally HIGH", "optc": "when all outputs are normally LOW", "optd": "when two or more outputs are connected to two or more inputs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A bidirectional 4-bit shift register is storing the nibble 1110. Its  input is LOW. The nibble 0111 is waiting to be entered on the serial data-input line. After two clock pulses, the shift register is storing ________.", "opta": "1110", "optb": "0111", "optc": "1000", "optd": "1001", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a parallel in/parallel out shift register, D0 = 1, D1 = 1, D2 = 1, and D3 = 0. After three clock pulses, the data outputs are ________.", "opta": "1110", "optb": "0001", "optc": "1100", "optd": "1000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The group of bits 10110111 is serially shifted (right-most bit first) into an 8-bit parallel output shift register with an initial state 11110000. After two clock pulses, the register contains ________.", "opta": "10111000", "optb": "10110111", "optc": "11110000", "optd": "11111100", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "By adding recirculating lines to a 4-bit parallel-in, serial-out shift register, it becomes a ________, ________, and ________-out register.", "opta": "parallel-in, serial, parallel", "optb": "serial-in, parallel, serial", "optc": "series-parallel-in, series, parallel", "optd": "bidirectional in, parallel, series", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of register would have a complete binary number shifted in one bit at a time and have all the stored bits shifted out one at a time?", "opta": "parallel-in, parallel-out", "optb": "parallel-in, serial-out", "optc": "serial-in, parallel-out", "optd": "serial-in, serial-out", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When an 8-bit serial in/serial out shift register is used for a 20 s time delay, the clock frequency is ________.", "opta": "40 kHz", "optb": "50 kHz", "optc": "400 kHz", "optd": "500 kHz", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ring shift and Johnson counters are:", "opta": "synchronous counters", "optb": "aynchronous counters", "optc": "true binary counters", "optd": "synchronous and true binary counters", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a shift-right register and a shift-left register?", "opta": "There is no difference.", "optb": "the direction of the shift", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a transceiver circuit?", "opta": "a buffer that transfers data from input to output", "optb": "a buffer that transfers data from output to input", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 74HC195 4-bit parallel access shift register can be used for ________.", "opta": "serial in/serial out operation", "optb": "serial in/parallel out operation", "optc": "parallel in/serial out operation", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of device may be used to interface a parallel data format with external equipment's serial format?", "opta": "key matrix", "optb": "UART", "optc": "memory chip", "optd": "series in, parallel out", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the function of a buffer circuit?", "opta": "to provide an output that is inverted from that on the input", "optb": "to provide an output that is equal to its input", "optc": "to clean up the input", "optd": "to clean up the output", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the preset condition for a ring shift counter?", "opta": "all FFs set to 1", "optb": "all FFs cleared to 0", "optc": "a single 0, the rest 1", "optd": "a single 1, the rest 0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not characteristic of a shift register?", "opta": "Serial in/parallel in", "optb": "Serial in/parallel out", "optc": "Parallel in/serial out", "optd": "Parallel in/parallel out", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To keep output data accurate, 4-bit series-in, parallel-out shift registers employ a ________.", "opta": "divide-by-4 clock pulse", "optb": "sequence generator", "optc": "strobe line", "optd": "multiplexer", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 50 kHz clock frequency, six bits can be serially entered into a shift register in ________.", "opta": "12 s", "optb": "120 s", "optc": "12 ms", "optd": "120 ms", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Another way to connect devices to a shared data bus is to use a ________.", "opta": "circulating gate", "optb": "transceiver", "optc": "bidirectional encoder", "optd": "strobed latch", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To serially shift a nibble (four bits) of data into a shift register, there must be ________.", "opta": "one clock pulse", "optb": "four clock pulses", "optc": "eight clock pulses", "optd": "one clock pulse for each 1 in the data", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Computers operate on data internally in a ________ format.", "opta": "tristate", "optb": "universal", "optc": "parallel", "optd": "serial", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a 4-bit Johnson counter sequence there are a total of how many states, or bit patterns?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 10-bit ring counter has an initial state 1101000000, what is the state after the second clock pulse?", "opta": "1101000000", "optb": "0011010000", "optc": "1100000000", "optd": "0000000000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How much storage capacity does each stage in a shift register represent?", "opta": "One bit", "optb": "Two bits", "optc": "Four bits (one nibble)", "optd": "Eight bits (one byte)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the output of a tristate shift register is disabled, the output level is placed in a:", "opta": "float state", "optb": "LOW state", "optc": "high-impedance state", "optd": "float or high-impedance state", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}